#### Lee Baillie

#### Software Developer

Mobile: 07944891239

Email: LW.Baillie@gmail.com

Portfolio: <a href="https://leebaillie.netlify.app/">https://leebaillie.netlify.app/</a>

## Professional Profile

I'm passionate about development with many years' experience as a .NET developer. As well as my development experience across various platforms I've also been a mentor and technical lead for multiple projects across different industries.

#### Skills

C# | VB.NET | Winforms | Web API | ASP.NET | HTML 5 | CSS | REACT | JavaScript | LINQ | VB6 | MS Access | Microsoft SQL Server | TFS | GIT | Scrum | Agile

## Career Summary

## **Application Developer**

**Opus Energy** 

2018 - Present // Northampton, United Kingdom

- Establish a detailed program specification through discussion with stakeholders and BSA's
- Clarify the actions the program is intended to perform
- Develop change requests and or organisation projects.
- Maintain existing features by making either minor or major modifications, based on the requirements.
- Work as part of a team which may be established purely for a particular project to write a specific section of the program
- Test sample data-sets to check that output from the program works as intended
- Devise possible solutions to anticipated problems
- React to problems and correct the program as necessary
- Evaluate and increase the program's effectiveness
- Adapt the program to new requirements, as necessary
- Support user acceptance testing, to ensure the program can be used easily, quickly and accurately
- Update, repair, modify and develop existing software and generic applications.
- Work in accordance with Agile, attending daily scrums and working to two-week sprints
- Independently created DTC file builder, a desktop application written in C# which builds industry dataflows.

## Technical Underwriting Manager/Application Developer Transactor Global Solutions 2010 - 2016 // Milton Keynes, United Kingdom

- Managed 22 developers and analysts to ensure that the software was delivered on time and within budget.
- Furthered the professional development of new hires by arranging training sessions designed to improve their knowledge and skill set in various aspects of their jobs.
- Oversaw the conceptualising of new projects and organisation of the company's work schedules and workflow which involved determining start dates for projects and allocating work to employees.
- Created detailed and summarised management information reports in order for relevant and high quality information to be communicated across the business.
- Implemented policies, rules and regulations to address key business issues and monitored them to ensure that they were being followed by employees.
- Reviewed CV's from prospective employees and determined whether they should be invited to interview.
- Conducted interviews with candidates to identify whether they possessed the required experience and Skills to be suitable for the position.
- Engaged with external stakeholders (insurance companies) when discussing ongoing and future projects and pricing details.
- Managed the release of software on a monthly basis by overseeing the work of those involved to ensure that the software was released on time.
- Liaised with the Directors when undertaking weekly conference calls.
- Wrote software by effectively utilising Visual Studio 2012-2015, Visual Basic. NET and C#.
- Developed and ran stored procedures and scripts by utilising SQL Server.
- Independently created EDI Manager, a desktop application written in C# which enabled thousands of policies to be sent to and from insurers in the form of messages via FTP/SFTP on a daily basis.

## EDI Manager Transactor Global Solutions 2004 - 2010 // Milton Keynes, United Kingdom

- Liaised with external stakeholders to discuss their EDI requirements such as the mechanisms for sending the data to them and the standards applicable
- Ensured that the EDI documents sent met the required standards, reducing the risk of the computers having issues in interpreting the information
- Tracked EDI message logs by analysing messages to ensure that they were generated correctly
- Fixed bugs in messages within a 7 day window by efficiently utilising VB, VB.net, XML and SQL server
- Monitored the EDI software to determine whether any enhancements needed to be made, and where this was the
  case, undertook development work within a timely manner

# Earlier Career History

2000-2004 HEAD OF PROGRAMMING DEPARTMENT, Brokersoft 1995-2000 UNDERWRITING PROGRAMMER/SYSTEMS ANALYST, Sprintgrace

#### Education

O'Levels: including Maths, English Literature, English Language, (1979-1984)